Register of the Günter Reimann papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Writings, 1925-2005
  - Herbert Wehner (Funk, Kurt)
    - Copy of an Article about Herbert Wehner (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Handwritten Notes (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Typewritten Notes (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Articles (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Imperialism
    - Introduction (Box-folder 29: 1-4)
    - Inflation (Box-folder 29: 5, Box-folder 30: 1-9)
    - IFS (International Finance System) (Boxes 31-33, Box-folder 34: 1-2)
    - IFS, German language versions (Box-folder 34: 3-5)
    - Debt Crisis (Box-folder 34: 6-7, Box-folder 35: 1-3)
    - Chapter IV (Box-folder 35: 4-6)
    - SSS (Soviet State Socialism) (Boxes 36-38)
- Autobiography/Memoirs
  Includes material, notes and whole drafts about persons, topics Arranged in alphabetical order and epochs (in chronological order, divided in German and English version).
  - Material and Drafts about Persons
    - Abusch, Alexander (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Barth, Eugen (Box-folder 39: 2)
    - Barthel-Kaetzler, Luise (Wise) (Box-folder 39: 3)
    - Becher, Johannes R. (Box-folder 39: 4)
    - Beriia, Lavrentii Pavlovich (Box-folder 39: 5)
    - Bessonov, Sergej (Box-folder 39: 6)
    - Bester, Willi (Box-folder 39: 7)
    - Beverage, Albion (Box-folder 39: 8)
    - Blessing, Karl (Box-folder 39: 9)
    - Brandler, Heinrich and Thalheimer, August (Box-folder 39: 10)
    - Brandt, Willy (Box-folder 39: 11)
    - Bucharin, Nikolai Ivanovich (Box-folder 39: 12-13)
    - Burns, Arthur (Box-folder 39: 14)
    - Calverton, Victor Francis (Goetz, George) (Box-folder 39: 15)
    - Collett, Alec (Box-folder 39: 16)
    - Dennis, Lawrence (Box-folder 39: 17)
    - Djilas, Milovan (Box-folder 39: 18)
    - Djojohadikusomo, Sumitro (Box-folder 39: 19)
    - Fischer, Ruth (Box-folder 39: 20)
    - Goldhammer, Bruno (Box-folder 39: 21)
    - Gorbachev, Mikhail Sergeyevich (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - Guddorf, Wilhelm (Braun, Paul) (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - Haffner, Sebastian (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - Harich, Wolfgang (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Hitler, Adolf (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - Hoelz, Max (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - Hu, Lan Xi (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - Jacobsson, Per (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - Jacoby, Walter (Box-folder 40: 9)
    - Jung, Franz (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - Kantorowicz, Alfred (Box-folder 40: 11)
    - Keynes, John Maynard (Box-folder 40: 12)
    - Koo, Antony Y.C. (Box-folder 40: 13)
    - Kuczynski, Jürgen (Box-folder 40: 14, Box-folder 41: 1)
    - Kun, Béla (Box-folder 41: 2)
    - Kurz, Robert (Box-folder 41: 3)
    - Leont'ev, Lev Abramovich (Box-folder 41: 4-5)
    - Levy, Benno (Box-folder 41: 6)
    - Libermann, Nina (Box-folder 41: 7)
    - Löwenheim, Walter (Miles) (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - Luxemburg, Rosa (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - Macdonald, Dwight (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - Makowski, Werner (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - Marx, Karl (Box-folder 42: 5)
    - Moser, Karl (Box-folder 42: 6)
    - Münzenberg, Willi (Box-folder 42: 7)
    - Neufeld, Fritz (Box-folder 42: 8)
    - Neugröschel, Anja (Box-folder 42: 9)
    - Neumann, Heinz (Box-folder 42: 10)
    - Norden, Conrad (Box-folder 42: 11)
    - Otani, Teinosuke (Box-folder 42: 12)
    - Padmore, George (Box-folder 42: 13)
    - Paresce, Ella and René (Box-folder 42: 14)
    - Pedrosa, Mariu (Box-folder 42: 15)
    - Perkins, Max (Box-folder 42: 16)
    - Platow, Robert (Box-folder 42: 17)
    - Radek, Karl (Box-folder 42: 18)
    - Rathenau, Walter (Box-folder 42: 19)
    - Roi, Max (Box-folder 42: 20)
    - Scharnowski, Ernst (Box-folder 42: 21)
    - Schinnagel, Arthur (Box-folder 42: 22)
    - Schulz, Otto (Box-folder 42: 23)
    - Seghers, Anna (Box-folder 42: 24)
    - Soros, George (Box-folder 42: 25)
    - Süsskind, Kurt (Box-folder 42: 26)
    - Stalin, Josef (Box-folder 42: 27)
    - Thälmann, Ernst (Box-folder 42: 28)
    - Utley, Freda (Box-folder 42: 29, Box-folder 43: 1)
    - Weiland (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - Wentz, Dietrich (Box-folder 43: 3)
    - Wittfogel, Karl A. (Box-folder 43: 4)
    - Wolfe, Bertram (Box-folder 43: 5)
  - Material and Drafts about Topics Arranged in alphabetical order
    - Angermünde (Box-folder 43: 6-7)
    - Asian Mode of Produce (Box-folder 43: 8)
    - Berlin (Box-folder 43: 9)
    - BVG-Strike, 1932 (Box-folder 44: 1-2)
    - China-Japan Finance and Capitalism (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Class Conflict (Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Cold War (Box-folder 44: 5)
    - Collective guilt and reeducation in Germany (Box-folder 44: 6)
    - Comintern (Box-folder 44: 7)
    - Communist Party of Germany (KPD) (Box-folder 44: 8)
    - Communists in the USA (Box-folder 44: 9)
    - Conservatism (Box-folder 44: 10)
    - Constructivism (Box-folder 44: 11)
    - Cooperation for American Remittances to Europe (CARE) (Box-folder 44: 12)
    - Depression (Box-folder 44: 13)
    - Dunkirk (Box-folder 44: 14)
    - European Monetary Union (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Family USA (Box-folder 45: 2)
    - Finance Capitalism (Box-folder 45: 3-6, Box-folder 46: 1-2)
    - Fordism (Box-folder 46: 3)
    - German Nation (Box-folder 46: 4)
    - Germany (Box-folder 46: 5)
    - Globalization (Box-folder 46: 6)
    - Gold (Box-folder 46: 7-8)
    - Historiography (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - Imperialism (Box-folder 47: 2-3)
    - Industrialism (Box-folder 47: 4)
    - Inflation (Box-folder 47: 5)
    - International Capital Market (Box-folder 47: 6)
    - International Currency System (Box-folder 47: 7)
    - International Monetary Fund (Box-folder 47: 8)
    - International Reports (Box-folder 47: 9-10)
    - International Reports (Reimann vs. Sat. Evening Post Co.) (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - Judaism (Box-folder 48: 2-3)
    - Keynesianism (Box-folder 48: 4)
    - Labor Movement (Box-folder 48: 5)
    - Left Wing Radicalism in Germany (Box-folder 48: 6)
    - Leisure and Freedom (Box-folder 48: 7-8)
    - Love, Sex, and Marriage (Box-folder 48: 9)
    - Madeira (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - Market and State (Box-folder 49: 2)
    - Mexico (Box-folder 49: 3)
    - Monetary Capital (Box-folder 49: 4)
    - Money (Box-folder 49: 5)
    - Morgenthau-Plan (Box-folder 49: 6-7)
    - Neoliberalism (Box-folder 49: 8)
    - New Deal (Box-folder 49: 9)
    - New York, USA, Impressions (Box-folder 49: 10)
    - Parental Home (Box-folder 49: 11)
    - Rote Fahne (Newspaper) (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Slums (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - Social Security (Box-folder 50: 3)
    - Socialism (Box-folder 50: 4-5)
    - Totalitarianism (Box-folder 50: 6)
    - Trading with the Enemy Act (Box-folder 50: 7)
    - Trotskyism (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - Working Class (Box-folder 51: 2)
    - USSR (Box-folder 51: 3)
    - Versailles, Weimar, Post War World (Box-folder 51: 4)
    - Youthful Subculture in the 1920s, 1930s (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Material and Drafts about Epochs Arranged in chronological order, German Version
    In chronological order
    - Tender Years (Box-folder 51: 6)
    - Adolescent Years (Box-folder 51: 7)
    - World War I (Box-folder 51: 8)
    - 1918-1919 (Box-folder 51: 9)
    - Civil War Germany, 1918, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 51: 10)
    - The 1920s (Box-folder 51: 11)
    - Stock Market Crash, 1929 (Box-folder 51: 12)
    - The early 1930s in the Resistance (Box-folder 51: 13)
    - The 1930s (Box-folder 51: 14)
    - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 51: 15, Box-folder 52: 1-3)
    - Reichstag Fire, 1933 (Box-folder 52: 4)
    - The mid 1930s Escape and Exile in Prague, Paris, and London (Box-folder 52: 5)
    - America, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 52: 6)
    - World War II (Box-folder 52: 7)
    - The Year 1945 (Box-folder 52: 8, Box-folder 53: 1)
    - Trip to Europe after World War II (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - The Year 1968 (Box-folder 53: 3)
    - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 53: 4)
    - After the Cold War (Box-folder 53: 5)
    - 1996-1997 (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - Material and Drafts about Epochs Arranged in chronological order, English Version
    - 1904, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 53: 7)
    - 1918/1919 -1930s (Box-folder 53: 8, Box-folder 54: 1-3)
    - 1930s (Box-folder 54: 4-5, Box-folder 55: 1)
    - 1939, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 55: 2)
    - After World War II (Box-folder 55: 3)
    - Trip to China, 1992 (Box-folder 55: 4)
  - Whole Drafts and Fragments Arranged in chronological order
    Including General Material
    - Undated (Box-folder 55: 5)
      (before 1990s (?) approximately oldest German Version)
    - circa 1994 (Box-folder 55: 6)
    - circa 1994-1995 (Box-folder 56: 1)
    - circa 1997 (Box-folder 56: 2-3)
    - circa 1999 (Box-folder 56: 4-5)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 57: 1-2)
    - Undated (Box-folder 57: 3-4)
      (only Part II)
    - Notes Undated and Untitled (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - Proposal Submittal Letter for Publisher (Box-folder 58: 2)
    - Contract of Publication (Box-folder 58: 3)
    - Biographical Information (Box-folder 58: 4)
    - Central Theme (Box-folder 58: 5)
    - Index of Names (Box-folder 58: 6)
    - Prologue (Box-folder 58: 7)
    - Abstract (Box-folder 58: 8)
    - Schedule (Box-folder 58: 9)
- International Reports on Finance and Currencies, 1945-1992
  Incomplete printed editions, arranged chronologically.
  - International post-war-service (International Statistical Bureau Inc.), 1945-1949 (Box-folder 59: 1)
  - International Statistical Bureau Foreign Letter (Box-folder 59: 2)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 59: 3)
  - 1950 (Box-folder 59: 4)
  - 1951 (Box-folder 59: 5)
  - 1953 (Box-folder 59: 6-7)
  - 1953 (Box-folder 59: 8)
    (only Statistical Market Letter)
  - 1954 (Box-folder 60: 1-2)
  - 1955 (Box-folder 60: 3-5)
  - 1956 (Box-folder 60: 6-7, Box-folder 61: 1)
  - 1957 (Box-folder 61: 2-4)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 61: 5)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 61: 6)
  - 1960 (Box-folder 61: 7)
    (only Special Notification)
  - 1960 (Box-folder 61: 8)
    (only Confidential)
  - 1962 (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 62: 2)
  - 1963-1965 (Box-folder 62: 3)
  - 1963-1966 (Box-folder 62: 4)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 62: 5-7)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 63: 2-4)
  - 1966 (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - 1967 (Box-folder 64: 1-4)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 64: 5-6, Box-folder 65: 1-2)
  - 1969 (Box-folder 65: 3-5)
  - 1975 (Box-folder 66: 1-5)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 67: 2)
    (only Foreign Letter)
  - 1983-1984 (Box-folder 67: 3)
    (only Foreign Service)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 67: 4)
    (only International Business Intelligence)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 67: 5)
  - 1985 (Box-folder 67: 6)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 67: 7-8)
  - 1992 (Box-folder 67: 9)
- Printed Matter
  - Books (Box-folder 68: 1-2)
  - Articles and clippings (Box-folder 68: 3-5)
  - Biography, Germany After WWII (Box-folder 68: 6)
  - Issues of Rote Fahne (Newspaper), 1920s/1930s (Box-folder 69: 1-4)